export const LITERATUREINENGLISHA2017 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. A praise poem is ____________",
A: "A Ballad",
B: "A Panegyric",
C: "An Allegory",
D: "An Epigram",
answer: "B. Panegyric",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. A literary work in which the characters are animals is a ____________",
A: "Lampoon",
B: "Fable",
C: "Parody",
D: "Pantomine",
answer: "B. Fable",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. A short single act drama is called____________",
A: "Opera",
B: "Allusion",
C: "Farce",
D: "Playlet",
answer: "D. Playlet",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Through the trees, I'll hear a single Ringing sound, a cowbell jingle  The underlined is an example of____________ryhme",
A: "End",
B: "Feminine",
C: "Internal",
D: "Masculine",
answer: "C. Internal",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Yet, let me flap this bug with gilded wings, This painted child of dirt, that stinks and stings The alliteration in stinks and stings effectively conveys__________-",
A: "Distaste",
B: "Admiration",
C: "Indifference",
D: "Approval",
answer: "A. Distaste",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Yet, let me flap this bug with gilded wings, This painted child of dirt, that stinks and stings The poets intention is to___________",
A: "Create Humor",
B: "Arouse sympathy",
C: "Create fun",
D: "Show Contempt",
answer: "D. Show Contempt",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Yet, let me flap this bug with gilded wings, This painted child of dirt, that stinks and stings The lines illustrates________",
A: "Blank Verse",
B: "End ryhme",
C: "Internal rhyme",
D: "Free Verse",
answer: "B. End rhyme",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. A play on words for literary effect is_________",
A: "A Paradox",
B: "A Pun",
C: "A Satire",
D: "An Elegy",
answer: "B. Pun",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. 'Its a matter of sad joy' Iillustrates__________",
A: "Metonymy",
B: "Oxymoron",
C: "Euphemism",
D: "Irony",
answer: "B. Oxymoron",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. The leading character in a literary work is the________",
A: "Foil",
B: "Villain",
C: "Antagonist",
D: "Protagonist",
answer: "D. Protagonist",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. A narrative poem that relates heroic exploits is an___________",
A: "Epilogue",
B: "Epitaph",
C: "Epic",
D: "Epigram",
answer: "C. Epic",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Over the cobbles it clattered and crashed is an example of__________",
A: "Oxymoron",
B: "Pun",
C: "Onomatopoeia",
D: "Paradox",
answer: "C. Onomatopoeia",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. An essential features of drama is___________",
A: "Soliloquy",
B: "Conflict",
C: "Irony",
D: "Aside",
answer: "B. Conflict",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. A humorous poem with five lines, the first two ryhming with the last is______________",
A: "An ode",
B: "Sestet",
C: "Octave",
D: "A Limerick",
answer: "D. A Limerick",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Death be not proud, though some have called thee might and dreadful is an example of___________",
A: "Euphemism",
B: "Metaphor",
C: "Apostrophe",
D: "Aliteration",
answer: "C. Apostrophe (Addressing death directly)",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. An essential part of the plot is____________",
A: "Characterization",
B: "Exposition",
C: "Atmosphere",
D: "Foreshadow",
answer: "B. Exposition",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. The climax in a literary work is the_____________",
A: "Middle",
B: "Beginning",
C: "Central part of the dialogue",
D: "Peak of the conflict",
answer: "D. Peak of the conflict",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Dramatis personae is the same as ____________",
A: "Chorus",
B: "Prompter",
C: "Foil",
D: "Cast",
answer: "D. Cast",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Ten thousand saw i at glance.......  Illustrates_________",
A: "Caesura",
B: "Climax",
C: "Bathos",
D: "Hyperbole",
answer: "D. Hyperbole",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Catharsis is normally associated with____________",
A: "Pantomime",
B: "Tragedy",
C: "Comedy",
D: "Farce",
answer: "B. Tragedy",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. The dominant feeling in the passage is that of______________",
A: "Hostility",
B: "Anger",
C: "Anxiety",
D: "Bitterness",
answer: "C. Anxiety",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. The feeling is conveyed by the use of_________",
A: "Long sentences",
B: "Visual images",
C: "Tactile images",
D: "Short sentences",
answer: "B. Visual images (e.g., 'death smelled in the air')",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Their silence spoke millions illustrates___________",
A: "Oxymoron",
B: "Litotes",
C: "Tactile images",
D: "Short sentences",
answer: "B. Litotes (Understatement: 'Their silence spoke millions' - meaning their silence conveyed immense worry)",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. The family bell summoned us is an example of__________",
A: "Apostrophe",
B: "Personification",
C: "Allusion",
D: "Euphemism",
answer: "B. Personification (Giving the bell the human action of 'summoning')",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. The passage is__________",
A: "In First person",
B: "In Third Person",
C: "A Dialogue",
D: "Monologue",
answer: "A. In First person ('I' is the narrator)",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. The first stanza is a ____________",
A: "Tercet",
B: "Couplet",
C: "Quatrain",
D: "Sestet",
answer: "C. Quatrain",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. The poem evokes the senses of_______",
A: "Smell and Sight",
B: "Smell and Hearing",
C: "Sight and Hearing",
D: "Touch and Smell",
answer: "C. Sight and Hearing",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. The dominant literary device used in the poem is_____________",
A: "Allusion",
B: "Repetition",
C: "Allegory",
D: "Metonymy",
answer: "B. Repetition ('rest awhile' is repeated)",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. The poet's tone is one of__________",
A: "Anxiety",
B: "Defiance",
C: "Nostalgia",
D: "Regret",
answer: "C. Nostalgia",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. My ears will drink by eager of choice illustrates________",
A: "Oxymoron",
B: "Onomatopoeia",
C: "Synecdoche",
D: "Meiosis",
answer: "C. Synecdoche ('ears will drink' - using a part to represent the whole)",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. The speaker is_____________",
A: "Duke",
B: "Othello",
C: "Brabantio",
D: "Cassio",
answer: "A. Duke",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. The tale being referred to is___________",
A: "Duke's war exploits",
B: "Brabantio's rejection of the Othello and Desdemona relationship",
C: "Othello's war exploits",
D: "Brabantio's rejection of Othello's love for his daughter",
answer: "B. Brabantio",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. ........this tale justifies_________",
A: "Roderigo's unrequited love for Desdemona",
B: "Cassio's promotion above Iago",
C: "Desdemona's attraction to Othello",
D: "Brabantio's rejection of Othello's love for his daughter",
answer: "C. Othello's war exploits",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. The underlined expression means___________",
A: "Seek counsel elsewhere",
B: "Wait till the war is ended",
C: "Take your revenge",
D: "Make the best out of this",
answer: "D. Make the best out of this (Accept the situation gracefully)",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. According to the speaker__________",
A: "The tale was good enough to win a woman's heart",
B: "The fight was unnecessary",
C: "The charges were a waste of time",
D: "There were other matters demanding the attention of the Senate",
answer: "A. The tale was good enough to win a woman's heart",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Othello is speaking to_____________",
A: "Brabantio",
B: "Duke",
C: "Montano",
D: "Roderigo",
answer: "A. Othello",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. The speech illustrates the use of________",
A: "Irony",
B: "Litotes",
C: "Paradox",
D: "Comic relief",
answer: "A. Irony (He is ironically praising Othello's military prowess while plotting against him)",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. A man he is honesty and trust refers to_________",
A: "Cassio",
B: "Lodovico",
C: "Gratiano",
D: "Iago",
answer: "C. Cassio",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Othello is leaving to__________",
A: "Fight in Rhodes",
B: "Make peace with the Turks",
C: "Meet the government of Cyprus",
D: "Take over the government of Cyprus",
answer: "A. Fight in Rhodes",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Othello then_________",
A: "Leaves with Desdemona",
B: "Entrusts Desdemona to Iago's care",
C: "Calls his lieutenant",
D: "Confers with the Duke",
answer: "A. Leaves with Desdemona",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. His soldiership refers to______________",
A: "Roderigo",
B: "Montano",
C: "Cassio",
D: "Brabantio",
answer: "C. Cassio",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. Sir refers to__________",
A: "Cassio",
B: "Roderigo",
C: "Othello",
D: "Duke",
answer: "C. Othello",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. Iago___________",
A: "Wants to go to Cyprus with Othello",
B: "Does not regard Roderigo as a good soldier",
C: "Is bitter about Cassio's appointment as Lieutenant",
D: "*******************************",
answer: "C. Is bitter about Cassio's appointment as Lieutenant",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. His eyes refers to____________",
A: "Lodovico",
B: "Cassio",
C: "Othello",
D: "Duke",
answer: "C. Othello",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. The setting is_______",
A: "The Castle",
B: "Cyprus",
C: "A sea-port",
D: "Venice",
answer: "D. Venice",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. The speaker is ________",
A: "Iago",
B: "Othello",
C: "Brabantio",
D: "Duke",
answer: "B. Othello",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. The first two lines express the speaker's_____________",
A: "Loneliness",
B: "Fear",
C: "Confusion",
D: "Regret",
answer: "B. Fear",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. The speaker has just_______________",
A: "Divorced his wife",
B: "Arrived home from war",
C: "Had a nightmare",
D: "Smothered his wife",
answer: "D. Smothered his wife",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. The speech is provoked by______",
A: "Emilia's call",
B: "Iago's treachery",
C: "Cassio's confession",
D: "Desdemona's plea",
answer: "B. Iago's treachery",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. The underlined expression suggests that____________",
A: "There is an imminent eclipse",
B: "Life will never be the same again for the speaker",
C: "Nothing will change",
D: "There is an impending danger for the speaker",
answer: "B. Life will never be the same again for the speaker",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},


]